Previously on "Vikings":
Hail, Earl Ragnar!
The seer prophesized that your
father would have many sons.
I'm with child again.
I know you're a boy - my son.
Lord Ragnar, I have come to swear
my allegiance to you and your family.
Leif, you are my friend.
- I would like to be a free man.
- Does it matter?
Everyone else in your
world is subject to the law.
Why do you say, "your world"?
You live here now.
This is your world.
You were once
married to an Earl,
would you not like to be married
to another one?
- Who?
- Me.
The gods desire
you to have a great future,
but they can withdraw
their good will at any time.
Our lives are fated,
we all have to accept that.
♪ More, give me more ♪
♪ Give me more
♪ if I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ If I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪ After the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I...
♪ If I had a voice
I would sing ♪
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
Resync for WEB-DL by Norther
Every nine years,
we travel to the temple
at Uppsala,
to give thanks to the gods and to offer
them sacrifices for all they do for us.
For protecting us,
for the success in battle,
for the rains that they bring
that grow our crops
and, of course,
for our children.
This year
I was not going to go,
for there is too much to do
around here.
Then my unborn son...
was cruelly taken from me,
and it made me wonder
what I had done
to anger the gods.
What do Christians do
about such pain?
In the Bible, it says that
all sorrows will pass.
In any case,
I've decided to go.
I'm going to take the children
for the first time,
for it's important
that they go.
What about you?
Me?
- What about me?
- Will you come with us?
Perhaps you would prefer
to stay here
and worship your own God.
No, I'll gladly come with you.
Good.
I would have taken you anyway.
A gift for the
gods, for the children.
Pray for my
daughter's recovery.
A gift for the gods.
Pray for health and prosperity.
My gift for the gods.
I ask their blessings
for my son.
Gyda, you take the offerings.
For the gods in
thanks for my new baby.
Thank you.
Ragnar...
Are you not happy
that we're going to Uppsala?
Of course I'm happy.
Why should I not be happy?
When we reach Uppsala,
we shall ask the gods
why they give with one hand,
but take away with the other?
Why they make me Earl,
yet kill my son?
We can have more sons.
Have we not tried?
Arne.
Gyda, step up.
Careful.
Ragnar.
Uppsala!
Floki!
Does he know?
No.
Hail to the
Aesir and the Vanir.
Hail to the gods and goddesses.
Hail to Odin, Thor, and frey.
Hail to Vali, Sif,
and Heimdall.
Hail to Balder, Bragi, and Eir.
Hail to Freja, Loki, and Frigg.
Hail to Lin, Ifon, and Mimir.
Hail to Njord, Ran, and Tyr.
Hail to Odin's spear,
Thor's hammer.
Hail to the mighty
fecund earth.
All...
All hail.
You know who
that is, don't you?
Of course.
This is Thor,
holding his hammer, Mjollnir.
Who hasn't heard him beating
his anvil in the storm?
Who doesn't believe in
mighty Thor,
slayer of frost and fire?
Freja, Loki, and Frigg.
Hail to Lin, Ifon, and Mimir.
Hail to Njord, Ran, and Tyr.
Hail to Odin...
Frey, Lord,
fill me with seed
and give me a son.
Do as you will with me,
make me blind
or deaf if you want to,
but give me a son
before it's too late.
- Hail to...
- All hail.
Hail to Freja, Loki, and Frigg.
Odin, father.
I have come to ask
for your love.
I want to grow and to prosper,
to quicken and be wise.
Hear me, Lord.
All hail.
Hail to the
Aesir and the Vanir.
Hail to the gods
and goddesses...
Lord of lords,
father,
hear my prayer.
Let me understand your will.
Is it true that I shall
have more sons
like the seer says?
Accept the sacrifice
I plan to offer you...
And then answer me.
Hail to the Aesir
and the Vanir.
Hail to the gods
and goddesses...
Hail to Odin, Thor...
Who will bear me my son?
Sif, and Heimdall.
Hail to Balder, Bragi, and Eir.
Hail to Freja, Loki, and Frigg.
How good is this, Rollo?
Especially because
we're here together.
Yes,
while we're here in Uppsala let us
enjoy and revel in every moment.
Have you been here before,
Helga?
No.
Do you know what happens here?
I've heard some stories.
And they're all true.
But they still don't prepare you
for what really happens here.
I can't wait to find out.
When is the food ready, Helga?
I'm hungry.
You're always hungry.
Of course I am...
but not always for food.
Can you feel it, Gyda?
Can you sense the presence
of the gods gathering here?
They have left
their bright halls to see us.
They are here for sure.
They walk among us.
And make their judgments on us.
So when do we offer
our sacrifices?
At the end of the festival.
And in the meantime,
we celebrate the gods
and enjoy their presence
in any way we can.
Give Athelstan a drink.
Priest... your cup.
Mother, you came here before?
Once.
And did you ask the gods
for anything?
Yes.
And they granted
my every desire.
What is this?
These will all be killed
as sacrifices.
Six, seven, eight, nine.
Seven, eight, nine.
And nine goats, and nine pigs.
There's nine of everything!
Yes,
nine of every kind.
And this?
It's for all the humans
that have been chosen.
Come join us, priest.
Drink.
Drink to the nights
and to the gods.
And, uh,
eat these.
I heard a rumor today that King
Horik himself may attend the festival.
It is not a rumor.
I desire to meet him.
There are great stories
and legends told about him.
Thank you.
You want to go out there,
don't you?
Please stay.
Why can't you stay?
Priest...
You are surely
not tired, Athelstan.
Not on this great journey
you have begun,
and must finish.
Leif...
If you let me go
I will fall again.
No,
the gods will hold you.
Priest,
I have been waiting for you.
Gyda, what is it, child?
I am bleeding.
Then you are no longer a child.
Forgive me.
You are a woman.
But let me cradle you
in my arms a last time,
as I always used to do.
It is hard for me
to let go of you.
Why do you do this, Thyri?
Don't you understand?
I have to.
Priests, stir yourselves!
- You ignorant peasant!
- Wake up!
- How dare you disturb us?!
Get out!
Get out of the temple!
Priests!
If you value your lives,
stop this at once.
Fools! This is King Horik.
Athelstan,
I want you to meet someone.
Ha! Ha! You
must be Ragnar Lothbrok!
I must tell you it is
my privilege and pleasure
to clap eyes on you.
Your reputation goes ahead
of you, Ragnar Lothbrok.
I know this because
so many have told me
how you killed Earl Haraldson
and then built
a new kind of ship...
were the first to sail west
and defeated a King of England!
In fact,
I can hardly believe my eyes
that you are standing right here
in front of me.
Please, please.
Travelers and
storytellers have described
how you came to your throne
by defeating, one by one,
the six uncles
that killed your father.
And my mother,
and all my sisters
and brothers.
I also know how you
favor the poets at your court,
and your people respect
your law making,
your justice, and your rule.
And as a consequence, here,
on this site,
in the living presence
of the gods,
I offer you my fealty
and my service.
I accept your pledge,
with a glad heart.
What can I do for you in return?
You could join forces with me.
I am not satisfied with what
I have achieved so far.
I want to send bigger
raiding parties to the west;
Yes, to plunder,
but also to explore new lands.
There are other lands
to the west?
There is a kingdom
called Frankia...
a kingdom far larger,
far richer,
and far more powerful
than England.
Athelstan, come.
Come.
This man has seen it.
I was a
Christian monk in England.
I traveled to other lands
as a missionary.
I have heard of Christians,
and of their God.
And are you still a Christian?
No.
Of course not!
How could you be a Christian
and walk among our gods?
I share your appetite
for new adventure,
Ragnar Lothbrok,
and I will gladly join forces
with you,
since, as king, I am naturally not
in favor of individual enterprise
by my earls, or anyone else.
But, believe me, I will be happy enough
just to have my name linked with yours
when the poets tell the story
of how we norsemen sailed west
and discovered new worlds.
Please, come. Eat, eat.
Why did you
bother to come back?
I was hungry.
Hmm.
How many women
have you been with?
- I don't suppose you know.
- I do what I want here.
I thought we came here
together.
We came here with Earl Ragnar.
I thought we came here
together and...
We did come here together.
We are together.
Why do you keep pestering me?
I am who I am
and I won't change,
not for you,
not for my brother,
not for anyone.
So leave if you want to.
But one day
I will be a great man
and you'll regret leaving me just
because I sleep with other women.
If you really want to be
a great man,
should you not be meeting
with King Horik now?
What do you mean?
Well, that's where
your brother is now,
and no doubt he's already boasting
about how he sailed west, alone,
and all he has achieved alone.
If you weren't so stubborn
and so drunk,
you would be there too,
but you weren't invited.
You didn't even know about it.
I could have told you.
You see, Rollo,
you need me
as much as I need you.
That is, if you really
want to be something.
Ragnar Lothbrok,
I drink to your good fortune.
May the gods continue
to favor you
and increase your fame.
May they do the same to you,
King Horik.
You have done me the honor of
pledging your fealty, as Earl, to me.
Forgive me, then,
if I seem anxious
to make use of your skills
and reputation...
As soon as possible.
To do what?
There is a Jarl in Gotaland,
Jarl Borg.
He is an important fellow, but he
continues to claim he has legal rights
over some of my land.
He threatens me.
He nearly invaded my
territory a year ago,
but at the last moment
he drew back.
And now, once again,
he is making
threatening noises.
And how can I be of help
in such a matter?
Would you be prepared to travel
to Gotaland as my emissary?
I can think of no one who I
would rather represent my case,
for your fame is widespread.
If the issue is settled,
I shall be forever
in your debt.
What do you say?
Come.
Have you come here
of your own free will?
Yes.
At first, I was
suspicious of you.
I sensed something,
so I spoke to Lord Ragnar.
He told me your story:
That you were a priest,
that you were a Christian,
and worshipped a God
called Jesus Christ.
Is that true?
Yes.
And do you still worship
this God?
Are you still, in your heart,
a Christian?
No.
Say again.
And a third time...
say it.
No.
You know why you're here,
don't you?
You have been brought here
as a sacrifice to the gods.
Athelstan:
I have come to tell you
that the sacrifice of this man
will not please the gods.
He is neither willing
nor is his faith acceptable
to Odin.
His heart is corrupt.
He has not renounced
his false God.
Looks like your God
finally came through for you.
Instead,
one amongst you must agree
to take his place tomorrow
at the sacrifice.
If not, then all shall fail.
The gods in their anger
will punish everyone,
and withdraw their protection
from all of us.
No, not you.
Before anyone else
can claim this honor,
I desire to be sacrificed.
For the sake of my family,
for the sake of all of you,
my friends.
But even more, for the sake
of all humans in Midgard.
I trust that the gods will find
my sacrifice acceptable.
In which case,
I look forward to it joyfully.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
Resync for WEB-DL by Norther