Ragnar:
Previously on "Vikings":
Earl Haraldson:
Do you understand that
all this belongs to me?
Rollo:
Why did you give everything
away so easily?
Ragnar:
Believe me,
this is not the end.
His name is Athelstan.
He speaks our language.
I want to sail west
again.
Earl Haraldson:
On one condition:
A warrior I trust
goes with you.
Knut:
I will take very close care
of your interests.
Ragnar:
I want to leave
as soon as possible.
I'll leave the priest
with a key.
You cannot place a slave
above me!
I want you to come
with me.
Ungh!
(men scream and roar)
Saxon rider:
Hi-yah! Hi-yah!
♪
♪ more,
give me more ♪
♪ give me more
♪ if I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪ after the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I...
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪
Hi-yah! Hi-yah!
(horse gallops)
(rooster crows,
sheep bleat)
(Saxon warrior pants)
(foliage crunches underfoot)
How far to hexham?
It's not far.
Are you sure?
Yes!
Arne: (excited)
Ragnar! Rollo!
♪
(foliage rustles,
branches and twigs snap)
(birds chirp)
Let's attack straight away.
No.
We attack tomorrow
Why wait?
(groans)
(sighs)
it is a large town.
We have only a few men.
Then surprise
is our biggest advantage.
Ragnar:
Arne,
What day is it today?
Saturday.
Then we attack tomorrow.
(steely)
you will understand tomorrow.
King Aelle:
Who were these strangers?
Saxon 2:
I cannot say.
Their ship was sighted
sailing up the coast.
It was a ship unlike any other.
Saxon 2:
No. They looked very different,
and used axes.
Most were as tall
as giants.
Noble 2:
Sire, I fear that these raiders
are the same pagans
Who attacked the monastery
at Lindisfarne.
It is the letter that
Abbot Alcuin wrote to you
Of those terrible events.
King Aelle:
"they came to the church
at Lindisfarne,
Laid everything waste
with grievous plundering,
Trampled the holy place
with polluted steps,
Dug up the altars
And seized all the treasure
of the holy church.
They killed
some of the brothers,
Took some away with them
in fetters,
Some they drowned
in the sea."
Where do they come from,
these pagans?
Some say from the north.
Well, wherever they come from,
They are not welcome
in my kingdom.
Floki:
(startled grunt)
(men laugh)
(blade rings
as it's sharpened)
Take care today.
Don't take any
foolish risks
And don't get separated
from the others.
I was just going to say
the same thing to you, my love.
Enough of that talk.
It's getting light
And we've wasted
too much time already.
We must wait
a little longer.
Leif:
Wait? What for?
Ragnar:
Just wait!
Knut:
For what?
Ragnar:
And listen!
(leif sighs)
Kauko:
I don't hear anything.
(church bells clang)
Ragnar:
Well, what are you waiting for?
(struggling grunts)
(axes thunk into place)
(feet thud on the palisade)
(geese honk, wings beat)
(footsteps crunch)
(geese honk nervously)
♪
(banging,
wood clatters)
♪
...Effundetur in remissionem
peccatorum.
(Ragnar listens to
the muted words of the priest)
(floki giggles)
Priest:
Hoc facite in meam
commemorationem.
Mysterium fedei.
(doors bang open,
Saxons cry out, shocked)
♪
(Saxons murmur nervously)
Brave men:
Aggggghhhhhh!
(weapons slash and slice)
Agh! Ungh!
(women scream in fear)
Shhh!
(Saxons murmur, frightened)
(Viking grunts tauntingly,
Saxons scream in fear)
In the name of God,
who are you?
Why have you come here?
This is a place of God.
If you do not resist,
we will not hurt you.
Tell that to your people,
priest.
Tell them not to be afraid.
God bless.
(Saxons murmur nervously)
(in anglo Saxon)
(cacophony of voices cry out
in protest)
(candelabras clank
on the ground)
(objects clatter and bang,
women scream)
(door bursts open)
(gasps)
(man coughs feebly)
(frightened gasps)
(weak whimper)
(water pours)
(coughing)
(water splashes)
♪
(Saxons murmur, upset)
(spits)
(Saxons cry out in horror
and anguish)
(floki spits,
Saxons cry out in horror)
(floki laughs)
(doors burst open)
(objects clatter and tumble)
(utensils clink)
(floor creaks,
utensils clatter)
(unsheathes weapon)
♪
(sheathes weapon)
(Saxons cry out in protest)
Priest:
Ungh!
(Saxons scream, horrified)
Boy:
Mom!
(struggling grunts)
(Knut grunts)
(woman sobs as she struggles)
Lagertha:
Knut! Leave her alone!
(Knut grunts, continuing)
Leave her alone!
What do you care
for this Saxon, you bitch?
Ungh!
(young woman weeps
and cries out)
(dull thump,
Knut grunts)
(grunts of effort,
weapons clank)
(Lagertha grunts in pain)
(fabric rips,
clothing rustles)
(hard thump,
Knut grunts in pain)
(hard stab)
(Knut cries out,
makes gurgling sounds)
(hard stab,
Knut grunts in pain)
(breathing rapidly)
(Knut thumps on ground)
(loot clatters and clanks,
Saxons scream and yell)
(horn bellows)
Ragnar:
(chuckles and sighs, pleased)
Where is Knut?
I killed him.
You killed him?
Lagertha:
He raped a Saxon woman.
Then he tried to rape me.
Did anyone else
see it happen?
That's a pity.
And where were you?
(loot clatters and clanks,
water splashes)
(waves crash ashore,
seagulls cry)
(man shouts a command,
Saxon soldiers cry out)
(dragging sound)
Hold!
What is it?
Who is there?!
Saxon prisoner:
(sighs with relief)
(loot clatters and clanks)
(waves crash ashore)
(readying inhale)
Saxon:
Archers front!
Shield wall!
(shields thump into place)
Saxon commander:
(yelling indistinct commands)
(arrows whoosh)
(arrows puncture
and clatter off shield wall)
(gasps)
(yelling command)
Saxon soldiers:
(screaming war cries)
Stand!
(soldiers crash
into shield wall)
(men shouting, roaring,
and screaming)
(weapons ring out,
clashing)
(men shouting, roaring,
and screaming)
Ragnar:
Open!
(arrow whistles)
(soldiers shout and scream,
weapons hacking away)
Rollo:
(shouting a Viking song)
up onto the overturned keel,
Clamber,
with a heart of steel,
Cold is the ocean's spray...
(arrows whoosh)
And your death is on its way,
With maidens
you have had your way,
Viking warriors:
Each must die some day!
(Vikings grunt
with renewed effort)
(weapons clanging
and clanking)
(shouting and screaming
fills the air)
(weapons clashing and hacking)
(hard blow,
Saxon screams)
(weapons clash and hack,
men scream and yell)
(hard blow,
Saxon screams)
Ungh!
Agghhhh!
Argh!
Lagertha: Ragnar!
Ragnar: Close the wall!
Lagertha:
Shield wall!
Ungh!
Aghhhhhh!
(weapons clash and clank)
(repeated hard blows)
(in norse)
(men shout and grunt,
weapons clash)
(Vikings roar, advancing)
Wigea:
Yah! Yah!
(Saxon men scream)
(horses whinny and gallop away)
(sudden stillness,
seabirds cry in the distance)
(waves wash ashore)
King Aelle:
How could this happen,
my Lord Wigea?
Wigea:
Sire, I have never in my life
seen men fight
As these northmen fight.
Believe me, there's something
devilish in the way they look,
In their lack of fear
in the face of death.
King Aelle:
My Lord, that is just
a counsel of despair.
Are these pagans not men,
like we are?
Do they not bleed
when they are cut?
Or do they have wings
and tongues of fire?
No, sire.
We captured two of them,
who were guarding their boat.
We couldn't understand anything
they said at all,
Except one word:
Ragnar.
(wind gusts,
fire crackles)
(Vikings murmur quietly)
Rollo:
Death is on its way
to take kauko.
Don't grieve for him.
Don't pity him.
Guess where he is now?
The valkyries are taking him
home to Valhalla.
Right at this moment
he is...
He is drinking ale
with the gods.
Yes,
He is happier
than even we are,
With our boat and...
These goods.
Erik:
Even so, he was my kinsman.
We must avenge his death.
It was done
in the name of King Aelle,
And King Aelle
must suffer for it.
One day, he will...
If the gods will it.
(Saxon prisoner whimpers)
Look at him,
He's wetting himself.
You kept your word.
You took us to the town,
and I thank you for that.
Drink.
You want to live?
(Saxon prisoner gulps)
(prisoner grunts)
(hard whack)
ungh!
Bjorn:
I want to go to Kattegat.
I want to see my father
return soon.
He must return soon.
I gave your father my word
That I would look after
you both here.
You are not
looking after us.
We look after ourselves.
I cannot allow you to go
on your own to Kattegat.
Your father would never
tolerate such a thing.
Bjorn:
Then we should go together,
The three of us.
Athelstan:
And who will then
look after the farm?
For what we are
about to receive,
May the Lord make us
truly grateful.
Amen.
(ale splashes into cup)
Gyda:
Can I have some ale?
You're too young, Gyda,
to drink ale.
I want to make a sacrifice
to thor,
For my father's safe return.
What will you sacrifice?
You!
(cup and bowl crash
on the floor)
(rough, scratchy rasp)
Athelstan:
(very quietly)
where are you, Lord?
Tell me:
Is it your will that I am here
with these heathens?
(wind howls outside)
How does it serve you?
I don't understand.
And for the first time
in my life
I am angry with you.
You allow my brothers
to be slaughtered and sold.
Is this really your will?
For the first time...
I feel lonely.
Where are you, Lord?
Where are you?
And why don't you
answer me?
(strange rustling
and shaking of feathers)
It's just an owl.
Bjorn.
Bjorn, wake up.
(exasperated groan)
what is it?
We'll go to Kattegat -
all of us - tomorrow.
(seabird cries)
Warrior:
Kattegat!
(excited shouting
in the distance)
Women and children:
(chatter excitedly)
(crowd buzzes with excitement)
(crowd shouts
and murmurs excitedly)
(crowd hushes)
Earl Haraldson:
Ragnar Lothbrok,
my friend,
How was your voyage?
Successful I hope,
For all our sakes.
(loot clatters and clanks)
Ragar:
The Saxons attacked us
when we returned to the boat,
In great force,
(shouts)
but we defeated them!
(crowd erupts in cheers)
You are the man
that people say you are -
A great adventurer -
And I am happy to salute
your achievements
And to share in the profit
of your raid.
But I don't see my friend,
Knut,
Where... Where is he?
Knut is dead.
Dead?
Did he die in the battle?
No.
Then how did he die?
I killed him.
You killed him.
For what reason?
Because he tried to rape
my wife, Lagertha.
I find it too convenient
That you would make
an excuse
To kill my friend
And my agent
on your voyage.
What did you think
that you would gain
By getting rid of him?
I didn't expect
to gain anything.
Earl Haraldson:
I don't believe you.
Arrest him!
Ragnar:
My Lord!
For your wife Siggy
Would have you not done
the same?
Svein:
I would counsel you all
against such actions.
There is no way
you could prevail.
Ragnar:
Floki.
Svein:
Bring him away.
Lagertha:
Ragnar! Ragnar!
(footsteps approach)
You summoned me,
Lord?
Yes,
I want to talk to you.
Please, sit.
Drink.
It's, um...
It's a delicate matter.
You...
You are the brother
of Ragnar Lothbrok,
Are you not?
I am.
A spirited man,
your brother.
Is he a fair man?
Does he treat you equally
when you sail with him?
Up to a point.
Forgive me, but I think that
he likes to rule you.
And that whatever he says,
In actual fact,
he considers himself
To be first among equals.
Am I correct?
(silence)
I get the impression
that he wants to...
To take the credit
for everything -
For building the boat,
for sailing west.
He wants to be the hero.
Is that what
it comes down to?
To him?
Would he have achieved
what he has achieved
If it wasn't for you?
(silence)
What do you say,
Rollo?
Of course not.
It would have been impossible.
As long as I am Earl,
Ragnar Lothbrok
can give you nothing.
I, on the other hand,
can give you a great deal.
I could, for example,
confiscate the treasure
That you brought back
from England...
And offer you
a goodly portion of it.
Would you do that,
Lord?
I might.
Depends.
On what would it depend?
Your ambition.
You want to stand out.
You want to be someone,
Rollo.
You want the gods
to notice you, yes?
Earl Haraldson:
Oh no, my friend.
And do you know why?
Because you still walk in
the shadow of Ragnar Lothbrok.
Don't you think it's time
you stepped out from it
And let the gods see you
for who you really are?
Oh! I want you to say hello
to somebody.
This is my daughter, Thyri.
She is soon to get married
And I must think very carefully
about her future husband.
He must be a man of ambition
and prospect,
As you can understand.
I used to have two boys
but they were killed.
So the man that I choose
to be my son-in-law
Will hold a high
and special place,
As if he were my own son.
Thyri, say hello to Rollo.
Hello.
Siggy:
Don't forget about me,
my love.
Earl Haraldson:
Oh, yes.
And this is Siggy,
my wife.
This is Rollo.
He is the brother
of Ragnar Lothbrok.
Hello, Rollo.
I have heard
a lot about you.
They say that you are
a great warrior.
(great hall buzzes
with chatter)
(door opens)
(everyone quiets down)
Svein:
Bring in the prisoner.
(crowd jeers loudly)
Woman:
That murderer!
(jeering)
Bjorn:
Look at him!
He's in chains.
It's all right, boy.
We are all aware of the sacred
nature of our duty here.
You stand before us
accused of the willful murder
Of Knut, my brother.
Knut, as some of you may know,
Was the bastard son
of my father.
But I loved him...
Like a brother.
I asked Knut to...
To go with Ragnar Lothbrok
to England,
Where they raided a town
and brought back many spoils.
And while they were raiding
this town,
Ragnar Lothbrok took it
upon himself
To cold-bloodedly kill
my brother.
Why a man like this
would do such a thing.
This is an ambitious man.
He doesn't care
to share his spoils,
And he resents the fact
That he owes me loyalty
and obedience,
As his chieftain.
This is a man who does not
believe in our traditions.
believe in our laws.
Crowd:
(sounds of disapproval
and disgust)
Svein:
Silence! Silence!
Earl Haraldson:
What do you have to say,
When you stand before us,
And know that you must tell
the truth?
It is that true
that I killed Knut,
Sadly, your brother.
But I killed him
When I found him
trying to rape my wife.
I ask all of you freemen,
What would have you done
if you were in my place?
Would have you
just stood back,
Encouraged the culprit?
I don't think you would.
And even if I had of known
at the time
He was your brother,
I would have carried out
the same sentence.
Svein:
Do you seriously ask us
to believe your story?
I can confirm the story.
(crowd murmurs)
You are the wife
of Ragnar Lothbrok?
I am, Lord.
How extraordinary that
you happened to be there
At the same time.
(crowd titters)
Your husband is lying
And you are so
under his thumb
That he has persuaded you
to lie for him.
May thor strike you dead!
(shouts of outrage
and disapproval)
Earl Haraldson:
What did you say?
My husband did not kill
Knut Tjodolf.
Svein:
Then who did?
Lagertha:
I did! I killed him.
When he tried his best
to rape me.
Svein:
A murder is committed
And the only witnesses
are a husband and his wife.
(crowd chuckles)
Unfortunately, we can't tell
who committed the crime
Because they both claim credit
for it.
You didn't kill my brother.
Look at you,
how could you?
He killed my brother.
Ragnar Lothbrok killed
my brother.
We have proof.
We have a witness
to the killing.
(whispers of surprise
run through the crowd)
Svein:
You say you are a witness
to the death of Knut Tjodolf?
Svein:
You'll swear this
upon your arm ring?
Yes, I was there.
I saw everything.
Earl Haraldson:
So, who killed my brother?
(fire snaps and crackles)
Ragnar Lothbrok
killed him.
(crowd murmurs)
In cold blood?
No, Lord.
For a good reason.
What Ragnar Lothbrok
has sworn is true.
Your half-brother was caught
raping a Saxon woman.
Then he attempted to rape
Ragnar's lawful wife,
Lagertha,
the shield-maiden.
So unfortunately...
You cannot punish him.
(chains jingle)
now who has the key?
(crowd buzzes with chatter)
(lively music plays)
(warriors chatter and laugh)
Woman: Come, Bjorn.
Man: Like father like son.
(laughing)
It seems I owe you
an eternal debt.
I know.
And I look forward
to collecting it.
Leif:
Let's drink a toast
to Ragnar!
To his future
and his freedom!
No, no, no, no.
To friends and freedom!
All:
Arne: (drunkenly)
not that he'll ever
be free of us!
(laughing)
Ragnar:
Will you drink with me?
Of course.
Thank you for taking care
of my children.
You're a good Christian.
(laughs)
(cup and blow clatter
and clank)
I wanted to say
thank you.
You did a fine
good thing, Rollo.
I hope the gods
were watching.
I didn't do it for him.
I did it for you,
shield-maiden.
I don't want to believe that.
Did you see Haraldson's face
when he had to acquit you
And then give you
half his hoard?
He looked like this!
(Ragnar and others laugh)
(laughing hysterically)
(Erik groans
while he takes a leak)
(sighs)
Ungh!
(grunting)
(struggling grunts)
(hard stab,
gurgled grunt)
(laughter and merriment halts)
Man:
Ragnar Lothbrok?
I am unarmed.
(swords ring
as they're unsheathed)
Get the children.
(attack cry)
(men shout and grunt,
stabbing and hacking)
Lagertha:
Hurry!
(fighting grunts,
stabbing and hacking)
Man:
Aaggghhhh!
(women cry out)
(men shout and grunt,
stabbing and hacking)
(incessant dripping)
Ellisef:
(weeping softly)
Leif:
Father.
(seabird cries)
(wind gusts,
seabird shrieks)
(chickens cluck,
pigs snort)
Ragnar:
Ungh!
(sheep bleat)
(forceful chop)
Ungh!
(axe clatters)
(logs thump loudly)
(water sloshes)
(geese honk noisily)
Seer:
Stones and bones.
Earl Haraldson:
What do you read?
Seer:
Wait. Not so impatient, Lord.
Earl harladson:
Tell me.
Seer:
Ask me a question
Are the signs...
Threatening?
Seer:
Yes.
There is a quarrel.
There will be violence -
Bones and skulls broken.
I see that.
(seabirds cry)
Athelstan:
What is Ragnar doing
sitting on the hillside?
Seer:
He searches for your death;
Consults the gods
to whom he claims kinship.
Who could believe
such a thing?
Does he desire to be Earl?
If he kills you,
will it not be so?
Do the gods speak?
Seer:
Do they ever stop?
Gods have always been
favorable to me.
They allowed yours sons
to die...
Earl Haraldson:
Do the gods really exist?
(the seer laughs)
I know what he's doing.
He's preparing himself.
♪