But I don't see Knut. Where is he?
I killed him.
He tried to rape my wife.
Arrest him.
My Lord, for you wife Siggy,
would have you not done the same?
Ragnar Lothbrok can give you nothing,
I on the other hand can
give you a great deal.
This is my daughter, Thyri.
She's soon to get married,
and I must think very carefully
about her future husband.
Ragnar Lothbrok killed my brother.
What Ragnar Lothbrok has sworn is true.
So unfortunately you cannot punish him.
Ragnar Lothbrok.
I am unarmed.
Does he desire to be Earl?
He searches for you death.
Consults the gods.
I know what he's doing.
He's preparing himself.
- provided by kabubuki / corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
May the gods protect you. Always.
Thank you, My Lord.
I hope your boy brings you profit.
That's the last one, My Lord.
Thank you.
May I ask you something?
Am I still your slave?
Does it matter?
It matters because I have
noticed that in your world,
slaves are often treated worse than dogs.
Do I treat you like a dog?
That's not my point.
Legally you could beat me to death,
and there would be no penalty.
But everyone else in your
world is subject to the law.
A man can rape his female
slave but not a free woman.
It is true that we distinguish
between those captured in battle,
and our own free men and women.
In any case, why do you say "your world"?
You live here now,
this is your world
and I've never seen you try to escape.
I am less and less
interested in escaping now.
Even if I could.
But I would like to be a free man.
If it matters so much to you.
It does.
What are you preparing for?
What do you mean?
I've watched you.
You are about to do something.
You have made yourself very strong.
Perhaps not strong enough.
What do the gods say?
What do you know about our gods, priest?
Finish the fish.
In silence.
Let the man who thinks that
he has descended from the gods,
learn that he is human after all.
We're under attack.
Gyda. Bjorn.
Get Bjorn.
Take this. Stay back.
Athelstan...
Take this.
What shall we do?
Should we run?
No, we stay.
Your father will be back.
But there are too many of them.
Stay strong. Be ready.
He's in the house, My Lord!
Father!
You're hurt.
We have to go now.
What's happening?
Father please tell me?
We have to get to the boat.
- Are you coming?
- Go.
Quickly, Gyda! Come on, boy.
Father, I won't go without you.
Boy, don't argue!
Father, I don't want to go without you.
Ragnar Lothbrok!
I'm right behind you. Now go.
Go on, quick. Go, boy, go.
Ragnar Lothbrok! Show yourself!
Show yourself!
Hi-ya! Hi-ya!
Come on. Come on.
Help! Help!
Do you accept that you are a criminal?
That you are only worthy only of defeat,
worthy only of death.
I accept my fate.
Let me speak with my God.
Get down!
Hurry!
Odin,
Lord of Lords,
Father, help me.
After him.
Burn the house!
Bring him back alive.
Yes, Lord.
Hi-ya! Hi-ya!
There!
There he is.
Where is he?
Can you see him?
Where is Father?
He's there somewhere.
Where are they?
Father!
Is he dead?
He's dead, isn't he?
He's dead!
Is he dead?
I don't know, Lord.
Seize his boat.
Yes, Lord.
He's a criminal.
He's not entitled to property.
Bring them here so we can talk to them.
Yes, Lord Haraldson.
You let him escape.
I will not forget that.
Floki!
Who are you?
I must speak with Floki. Is he here?
Bjorn?
My father is dying.
Helga, get the bark of the ash,
and the garlic and the sage.
Get the sage.
We make a paste to put on the wounds.
But first we must clean them.
And the only way to make
them clean is with fire.
Bjorn, get more logs back there.
A knife...
We must bid welcome to our guest.
Guest? You didn't tell
me to expect a guest!
This is Earl Bjarni.
He is a Swede.
This is my wife Siggy
and my daughter Thyri.
You are welcome, My Lord.
Thank you. It was a very
hard crossing, I must say.
You're right.
She's very pretty, My Lord Haraldson.
Come, feast with us.
Sit over here.
So that you may get to know
each other a little bit better.
Forgive me,
but why would they get
to know each other better?
Because they are being married.
- But he's...
- It's arranged.
May I?
You will have no regrets, my dear child.
And you will provide me with many sons,
of that I am quite certain.
The celebration, shall be later this year,
when I shall return, laden with gifts.
In the meantime,
please accept this as
a token of my affection.
Here, let me.
What do you say, Thyri?
Thank you, My Lord.
You are very... kind.
Give that to me.
I dedicate this blade to the goddess.
To Freya.
Wisdom might you give us, Freya,
and healing hands while we live.
Hail to the aesir.
Please Freya, heal my father.
For everything there is a season,
and a time for every matter under the sun.
A time to be born, a time to die;
a time to plant,
and to pluck up what is planted;
a time to kill, and a time to heal...
Mary mother of God, listen to me:
Do no let this man die.
How could you?
It's an excellent match.
He's a powerful man,
and he's the cousin of King Horik.
You don't judge a man by the way he looks.
We've struck a good deal.
He'll give us twenty
pounds of silver for her.
Don't you care for her happiness?
I care for her security, and her future...
and ours.
This marriage will bring us land
and important alliances.
The gods have seen that we need them.
You told me nothing of this marriage.
You have treated me with utter contempt.
You don't care.
I stopped caring about a lot of things...
when our boys were murdered.
They died... you buried them.
And for you, it was the end of the matter.
But for me!
They were my sons.
I bore them.
I brought them into this world.
I watched them as they grew.
And I loved them, just as I loved you.
The killers,
they dug a shallow grave.
And before they buried them,
they cut their heads off.
And when they laid them
in the ground, they...
they put their faces against their asses
as a sign of disrespect.
If I ever find the men
who did that... I will...
I took these locks of
hair from their heads.
See Siggy,
when you have such knowledge,
being married to a rich,
old man isn't so bad.
Is it true he's here?
He's still weak...
but his wounds are beginning to heal,
thanks to Floki's magic.
Torstein.
Ragnar, see who's here.
Ragnar, my friend...
How are you?
Save me from these people.
How did you know I was here?
I didn't.
I only know Earl Haraldson
is looking for you.
It was Rollo who said that if you're alive,
you might be here.
Then why did he not come himself?
Because he thought the Earl's men
would be looking for him especially.
It is no secret that all of
the crew are being watched.
But I made sure no-one followed me.
Let's eat.
It is good to see you.
You too, my friend.
This is Helga.
Hello Helga.
Oh, don't wiggle your maggot in her face.
She's taken.
Sit down.
I heard they burned down your farm.
They also slaughtered all our livestock.
We have nothing left.
You are alive.
Ragnar is alive.
Your children are alive.
You have everything left.
We also need to eat.
And we are already eating some
of your winter supplies, Floki.
And I am ashamed.
The gods will provide.
For everything there is a season,
and a time for every matter under heaven:
A time to be born, and a time to die...
Just eat your soup, priest.
Sometimes your God sounds
a lot like one of ours.
Why did the gods keep me alive?
That is the question I keep asking myself.
What are you going to do?
I can do nothing until I am well.
Where's the boat?
Haraldson has confiscated the boat.
His daughter is getting
married to man from Svealand.
The boat is her dowry.
Floki can always build us another one.
And the Earl?
Pssst!
Come on.
Torstein: What for?
If you don't come now,
I promise, you will regret it.
I don't remember inviting you
to my daughter's wedding.
Well, My Lord, I assumed
you'd just forgotten.
So I came anyway.
Here's to happiness for your daughter
and may she be blessed with many sons.
That could be you
dancing with my daughter.
I often think about it.
Still I was not fated to marry her.
I think that that old man was.
Why are you here?
We should talk.
Silence! Silence!
Earl Haraldson it is
time for husband and wife
to go to the matrimonial chamber.
So, what do you want to talk about?
I don't want your thugs,
like these fellows,
following me around everywhere.
It's a waste of everyone's time.
Oh, I disagree.
If you lead them to Ragnar Lothbrok
it will be time well spent.
Ragnar is dead.
Do you swear that on your arm-ring?
No.
I cannot swear because
I have not seen a body.
But I have heard nothing,
and he is my brother.
I am sure in my heart he is dead.
What about his wife and children?
They too have disappeared.
So I heard.
That you had them killed,frankly.
By these fellows there.
So why should I trust you,
because you've already betrayed me.
I didn't betray you.
I told the truth.
Shouldn't you trust
someone who tells the truth?
So tell me the truth now!
The truth is, you run everything here.
You own the ships.
You decide where it is we raid.
I need to be part of that.
I don't want to be on the outside.
I want to raid and fight.
It's what I was born to do.
I understand.
And you must understand
it will take time for me to trust you.
And I do not give my trust easily.
But you can stay here, eat at my expense,
work on my boats,
prepare for the season.
Then we shall see.
Agreed?
Agreed.
Good.
So if Odin lives in Valhalla,
is he the only God who
lives in a great hall?
No, there are many halls.
Thor lives in Thrudheim.
And Frey was given the hall at Alfheim
when he cut his first tooth!
And nearby is Valhalla,
vast and gold-bright.
And every day,
Odin chooses slain men to join him.
They arm themselves
and fight in the courtyard.
They kill one another;
but every night they rise again,
and ride back to the hall, and feast.
The roof is made out of shields.
The rafters are Spears.
Coats of mail litter the benches.
A wolf stands at the Western door
and an eagle hovers above it.
It has five hundred and forty doors,
and when Ragnarok comes,
eight hundred warriors
will march out of each door,
shoulder to shoulder.
What is Ragnarok?
Well then: How was the Earth created?
The Earth was made from the Ymir's flesh
and oceans from his blood,
when the titan was thawed from the ice.
The gods, they made hills out of his bones,
and trees from his hairs,
and the sky dome is his skull.
And out of his brain
they shaped the welling dark clouds.
So, how do you think it was made, priest?
Siggy.
No...
I was sure!
I've come to warn you:
You must leave at once. Today.
My husband he hates you.
He has shown me nothing but respect
since I came here.
Rollo, believe me. Get away.
Where's Ragnar Lothbrok?
Where is he?
He's dead.
Are you sure?
You said you always tell the truth.
You seem to have a little
trouble opening your mouth.
Perhaps I could make that
a little easier for you.
When will you be better?
It's taken too long already.
In a few weeks' time your
father's wounds will be healed.
If he is careful.
You must have patience, Father.
Shut-up.
Bjorn Torstein!
I found him wandering around the marshes.
I was lost.
I was visited in great secrecy
by Earl Haraldson's wife, Siggy.
She told me that her husband
had played a trick on rollo,
and imprisoned him, trying
to find where you were.
Then he tortured him.
He tortured my brother?
Yes.
Siggy is sure,
her husband means to kill him
because rollo will not,
in any way, admit to where you are.
It's a trap for you, Ragnar.
Floki,
I have another favor to ask you.
I want you to go in to Kattegat.
I want you to ask for
a meeting with the Earl.
And when you meet him,
challenge him to a personal combat.
With me.
Tell him, if he refuses
shame will stalk him
for the rest of his life,
and Odin will never
permit him into Valhalla.
- provided by kabubuki / corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -