Previously on "Vikings":
Aghhh!
The gods desire
you to have a great future.
Hail, Earl Ragnar!
How will we ever be equal now,
my brother?
I'm with child again.
I know you're a boy - my son.
We have to leave here. They
will shun us like a bad smell.
No one will force you
to go anywhere.
They wouldn't dare.
I have been a
warrior all my life.
I beg you, lord,
gift me the chance
to die with honor in battle.
Let's take him with us.
Aye!
Are these pagans
not men like we are?!
Do they not bleed
when they are cut?!
Let us prepare
to defend ourselves.
They're not welcome
in my kingdom.
♪ more, give me more ♪
♪ give me more
♪ if I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪ after the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I...
♪ If I had a voice
I would sing out ♪
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
Make way there! Come on!
Make way! Make way!
Brother!
Brother! Where are you?
Aethelwulf?!
Thank God you are come.
What on earth
made you think I would not, sire?
No, I never doubted you.
But others...
Our own youngest brother,
fled to Mercia.
He was always the runt
of the litter.
Our parents should've
drowned him at birth.
Where are the heathens now?
Only one, perhaps two days away
and your forces are ready
and armed?
Yes, if you are ready
to lead them.
I would regard it
a great honor, sire,
to defend thy kingdom
and our homeland.
And there's no
man better, lord Aethelwulf.
The poets sing
your battle praises
in the halls.
That's because I paid them.
If you paid them,
they'd sing your praises too.
That's poets for you!
My lady, pray,
have you no time for laughter?
No, my lord Aethelwulf,
only for fear.
How soon will they come?
Soon enough.
I hope so.
I can't wait for Valhalla.
Good day to you, folk.
What is the problem here?
The problem is her!
What has she done?
She has had a
child - the boy in her arms.
What of it?
He's not my child.
We tried for many years
to have children,
but without success.
And then, just over a year ago,
a young man came to the door.
I remember the day,
I was making a loom.
The young man
said his name was Rig.
He gave us some good advice
on our work
and stayed at our house.
After three days, he left...
And then nine months later,
she gave birth to a son.
Whose child is it?
I do not know, my lady.
We were all in the same bed.
I was too scared-you see?
She is not an honest woman.
She had sex with Rig,
and could not bring herself
to tell me the truth!
Do you know who this Rig was?
No. He was just a young man.
On the contrary.
We know from
our ancient stories
that Rig is another name
for Heimdal.
The God Heimdal?
My lady!
Yes, the God Heimdal!
You are fortunate
that he chose your household
to appear in.
That's just a story!
Our whole lives
are just stories.
You should be ashamed
you did not trust your wife,
despite the joy and comfort
she has brought you,
and the fact that a God
chose you
of all people to visit.
Do not punish her,
but rejoice with her.
Drink wine with her.
And sacrifice
one of your animals
to Heimdal the God.
But if I hear
you have harmed this woman,
or this child,
you will answer for it to me!
It seems they
intend to stay here a while.
I had not expected that.
My lord, why don't we attack?
They have a strong position.
Perhaps if we can make them
leave their position
and attack us.
How can
we force them to do that?
They're scavengers,
little more than beasts.
We must be able
to out-think them.
Saxon warrior 2
if we leave it much longer,
they'll be even better dug-in.
My lord, if a wolf comes
into your sheep fold,
you don't try to out-think it.
You go in and drive it away,
- or kill it!
- How dare you argue with me?!
Lord Aethelwulf,
forgive us. We only meant...
I know what you meant.
You meant that you're already
greater warriors than I am...
although only yesterday
you were still green
sucking on
your mother's breasts.
Go do your jobs. Set up camp.
You see them up there?
Yes, I can see them.
What're we waiting for?
To see what they'll do.
So you want to hand them
the initiative.
We can't afford
to lose half our men
by being stupid and attacking.
We wait until the odds
are in our favor.
Shh... shh... shh...
Shh...
Awake! Awake! Under attack!
Agh!
- Arm yourselves!
- Rise! Rise!
Run! Run!
Odin!
They're on us! Weapons!
Ungh!
My lord! We're being attacked!
Amen.
Who are you?
I'm lord Aethelwulf,
brother of king Aelle.
You are the
brother of the king,
yet you lead his army?
Hmm.
Does he send you to fight
all his battles?
In the bedroom too?
Ragnar!
Come and see!
Their iron is stronger
and better than ours.
And we've captured
a dozen of their horses.
I'm hungry already!
What ails you my friend?
The gods won't lift my curse.
I am fated to live forever
on this miserable earth.
Who is this?
This?
This is the king's brother.
What do you say?
Shall we go visit the king?
God help us!
My brother defeated. Dead.
God help Northumbria.
Sire, we do not
know if your brother is dead.
But we do know, my
lord, that he was defeated!
Who are these barbarians,
these savages?
Why have they come
to torment us?
Sire, some learned and wise men
say that these northmen
have been sent here by God
to punish our people
for their many sins
and transgressions.
That we have departed from
the path of righteousness
that our lord set out,
so now he is holding us
to terrible account.
Forgive me, sire,
but what if God has not
sent these northmen here
to plague us?
Then who has, pray?
Could it not, sire,
rather be the work
of the devil?
Go on then, my lord.
What is your advice?
Noble 3
my advice, sire, is that,
as we are facing
the forces of Satan,
we must resist them
at all costs.
Even at the cost of...
Of all our lives,
if necessary.
For evil cannot be accommodated
nor yet ever bargained with.
Aye!
Sire, if I might speak?
I-I put it to you
that it might be that
these pagans have come here
by their own account,
and that they are neither
of God
nor the devil.
They are just savage men
more interested in robbery
and plunder
than in matters of the spirit.
Then what is your advice?
Sire, since
they have come for gain,
then let us offer them
enough money,
or whatever else they desire,
to go away
and leave us in peace!
Shame! Shame on you!
Shame on you!
He is right!
Why waste more blood?
Let's pay them off!
My lords,
let me think on it,
just a little while.
In the meantime,
let it be known
I have sent envoys out
to raise more men to arms,
for our use if need be.
Long live the king!
Contend, o lord,
against those
who contend with me;
Fight against those
who fight against me!
Draw the spear and javelin
against my pursuers;
Say to my soul,
"I am your salvation."
Sire, they are here.
Greetings.
King Aelle invites your leader
to meet him in his villa
to talk.
Who is your leader?
The king did not know that
his brother was still alive.
He would like to talk to you
about what he can give you,
to set his brother free.
Do you accept
the king's invitation?
Where are you going?
We should attack,
while they are weak.
How long will it take them
to raise another army?
Attack, attack, attack!
That's all he ever says.
I want to talk to the king.
What is there to talk about?
Imagine the treasures
the king keeps
in his household?
I want them.
I want to see how he lives...
What manner of men they are,
and I'm hungry.
If we agree
to walk into his house
he can kill each
and every one of us.
You forget, we
hold his brother hostage.
Why should he care
about his brother?
Do I not care about mine?
They're coming!
My lord Eadric.
Sire, this
man is Ragnar Lothbrok,
his brother rollo,
and their companions.
Ah yes, Ragnar Lothbrok...
We've heard that name before.
We are pleased
you have decided to talk to us.
Perhaps, sire,
you should invite them
to eat first.
Forgive me.
Let us feast together...
And then talk.
_
The king!
Ragnar Lothbrok,
may I present my wife Ealswith,
and my son, egbert.
Hello.
Go on now.
In the name of
the father, and of the son,
and of the holy spirit, amen.
Amen.
Shall we talk, king?
Very well.
What do you want,
for the safe return
of my brother
and for leaving my kingdom?
Is he a priest?
He's a bishop of our church.
A man of God.
I too have a man of God
at home.
Two thousand pounds
in gold and silver.
What did he say?
How much?
Two thousand pounds.
I do not think I heard you
properly, Ragnar Lothbrok.
Hmm...
Two thousand pounds in weight.
That is the price.
I agree to the terms.
Good.
But first...
You must return my brother.
When we receive payment,
you shall have your brother.
You must give me time
to collect such a vast amount.
And in the meantime,
you and your men must remain
in your camp
and make no further attacks
on my people
or their property.
Agreed.
Sire! How can we
trust the word of a pagan?
Let me baptize one of them.
There is one further condition.
I desire that either you,
or one of your companions,
agrees to be baptized
into our faith.
And that way,
I can make peace with a friend
and fellow Christian...
And not an enemy.
You want one of
us to become Christian?
Yes.
Tostig!
I... will be Christian.
My lady Lagertha,
I hope you can find it
in your heart
to speak to the wife
of the late Earl.
Of course. Hello, Siggy.
Please sit down and join us.
Bjorn wait!
Earl Haraldson tried
to kill my father.
I know.
And if he had succeeded,
I would be standing
where Siggy's standing now.
So what would you like me
to say to her?
I would ask her to sit down.
Thank you.
What can I do for you?
It is what I can do for you.
I want to serve you.
That is not necessary.
I remember very well
how I served
the father of my church,
and it did me no harm.
In fact, I found in service
a great freedom and honor.
When I accepted that I should
forget about myself
and serve father Cuthbert...
Well... then I became happy.
If it's really what you want,
I accept your offer.
Thank you.
You and your daughter
are now under my protection,
but I will never treat you
as a servant.
O lord, holy father,
almighty and eternal God,
expel the devil and his
kin from this person:
From the head, from the hair,
from the brain, from the brow,
from the ears,
from the nostrils,
from the mouth,
from beneath the tongue,
from the throat, from the neck,
from the chest, from the heart,
from the entire interior
of the body,
from the thoughts,
from the words,
and from the deeds,
in the name of Jesus
Christ our lord.
Amen.
I anoint thee...
In the name of the father
and of the son
and of the holy spirit.
Amen.
Et spiritus sancti.
I now pronounce
you baptized and born again,
with the new Christian
name of Rolf.
May the lord bless you
and keep you,
from this day hence,
and for ever.
Amen.
We have
witnessed a true miracle.
Now I ask you to fulfill
your promises,
return to your ships,
and await your payment
in peace.
Agreed, Ragnar Lothbrok?
What is it?
I can't sleep.
Come here, beside me, daughter.
What worries you?
I fear for father, so far away.
Our lives are fated, Gyda.
We all have to accept that.
I can feel it moving
underneath my hand.
Mm-hmm. He has a strong kick.
He? Are you so sure it's a boy?
A long time ago,
the seer prophesized
that your father
would have many sons.
That's how I know it's a boy.
Now sleep.
Oh!
I won again!
Well done... Rolf!
What's wrong with you, Floki?
Oh, there's nothing wrong
with me.
I did not renounce the gods
in front of everyone.
It was a joke.
I didn't believe it.
I didn't even know
what the old fool was saying.
It doesn't matter.
Surely you've made them
very angry.
Don't be stupid.
No, you are the stupid one...
To risk the wrath of the gods.
How will you ever get odin
to forgive you now?
They're here! Come and see!
Agh!
They're empty.
Ungh!
Move back!
Fight back! Regroup!
Stay together!
Pull up!
Aggghhhhh!
Ungh!
Aghhh!
Agghhh! Ungh!
- Agghhhh!
- Ungh!
Aggghhhhhhh! Agh! Odin!
Aggghhhhhhh!
Aggggghhhhhh!
Ungh!
Aggggghhh!
Noooo!
Aggghhhhh!
Agghhh!
Aggghhhh! Ungh!
Aghhh!
Ungh!
Agghhh!
How many christians did I kill,
Floki?
How many?
Do you think odin
is still angry with me now?
Whew!
It seems your brother
the king...
Does not care if you live
or die.
If you let me talk to him,
I will persuade him
to honor his pledge.
Why should I not...
Just kill you now?
Then you'll have nothing left
to bargain with.
I have this.
Open!
Open the gate!
I swear before God almighty,
I declare war eternal
on the Northman
Ragnar Lothbrok.
I swear to our lord
Jesus Christ
and to the blessed virgin
one day I will avenge myself
on him,
and bring him to justice
and to death,
so help me God.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com