Previously on "vikings":
Odin gave his eye
to acquire knowledge.
I would give far more.
We will raid east again.
Every year we go
to the same places,
but there is an alternative.
They're my ships
and they go where
I tell them to go.
That's the end of the matter.
We should sail west.
Can't sail across
an open ocean.
I have something
that will change everything.
You keep talking about the west.
I believe...
I don't care what you believe.
Don't ever stick your nose
in my face again.
The boat will be lighter
and faster than before.
Do you think it could handle
long sea voyages?
We won't know
that until we try.
We must find a crew.
Not many men will go against
the wishes of Haraldson.
Some may even go to him
and betray us.
♪ more,
♪ give me more
♪ if I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪ after the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I...
♪ If I had a voice
I would sing ♪
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
Erik.
Ragnar Lothbrok,
welcome to my house.
You also, rollo.
I've done as you asked, Ragnar,
and sought out these young men
to meet you.
All of them have sworn
upon their rings
to keep this meeting a secret.
You have done well, my friend,
although I knew
I could trust you.
What are we here for?
You are here, firstly,
because you have
nothing better to do.
See, all you lot
live idle and wasted lives.
Listen to him!
We have built a new boat.
And with this boat,
for the first time,
we can go west.
Across the great sea,
to a place called England,
where countless riches await us.
How would we
steer across the open sea?
We have discovered a way.
You want us to
join you in the boat?
Yes, we do.
And I have Ragnar's word
that we will all be equal
and share equally
the spoils of our raid.
If there are any.
What is your name?
Knut.
I promise you, Knut,
I've heard witnesses.
Just stories.
Just stories...
All things begin and end
as stories.
We have to remember, though,
that Earl Haraldson
has ordered us to sail east.
The Earl knows nothing about
our new boat.
He knows nothing about
the new way of navigating.
This is why he refuses
to let us go west.
He could kill us for
disobeying his orders.
Yes, he could.
We can offer you a chance
to shine in battle
and impress the gods,
and to bring back such plunder
that you have never seen before.
Have you got the balls
to join us?
I'll go.
- And I.
- I will go.
I too! I will too!
And I! I will go!
What about you, Knut?
Are you coming?
Yes, I want a good story
to tell my children.
Ahh!
Prepare to leave
in the next few weeks,
and tell no one
that doesn't need to know.
- Good throw.
Well played.
Well?
My lord, there was a meeting.
Where?
In the house of Erik Marteinn.
Was Ragnar Lothbrok there?
Yes, lord.
Shall we show them the axe?
Nothing would please me more,
but it's too soon.
We need to watch and wait.
Only good things
come from watching...
And waiting.
Were you looking at my wife?
Have you slept with her?
No, lord!
I swear on all the gods.
If she wants to sleep with you,
then I give my permission.
It will be arranged.
So when do we sail?
I already told you.
I don't want you to come.
Why not?
I need to leave the children and
the farm in the hands of someone I trust.
What if the Earl finds out we
have gone without his permission?
He might try and claim
our family home.
This was going to be
the most exciting voyage
of our lives.
To go west!
I have dreamed of it
many times,
and in my dreams
we are always together.
What if there is no west?
This is the most dangerous
and stupid voyage ever.
What if we both die, hmm?
Then who would take care
of the children...
rollo?!
You have no right to say that!
All right, all right. You go.
You go
and I shall stay here
and look after the children.
Siggy?
Go away!
It's so cold in here,
but we'll be warm soon enough.
What do you take me for?
Did you really suppose
that a worm like you
could sleep with a woman
like me?
I'm an Earl's wife!
Now I know who to trust
and who not to trust.
- Take him.
- Yes, lord.
Get rid of him.
Come.
Outside.
Ungh!
Get up!
My love!
Never mind that.
Defend yourself.
How dare you?
Am I not good enough for you?
Am I not strong enough for you?
Ungh!
Now listen...
- You listen.
- Ungh!
Don't you remember?
I saved your life.
Ragnar how could I forget?
You keep reminding me.
Ungh!
I'm so angry with you!
Stop!
Are you mad?
You could have killed
each other!
Is that what you want?
We were just
having an argument.
Well, never argue
like that again.
Go on then!
Back to bed!
It's a fine thing
when the little pig teaches
the boar a lesson.
Ungh!
Olafur surprised me.
I didn't think, out of all of
them, he would behave like that.
A man lives or dies
by his honor.
That's true.
He thought so little of mine
that he really believed
that I would give you to him.
Honor is a rare commodity
these days.
Yes.
Almost as rare as those
in whom I can trust.
It's true, my love,
our enemies are everywhere.
Everywhere?
They cannot prevail.
Rollo.
Where is my anchor?
It was promised for today.
Maybe your blacksmith
is a liar.
I don't think so.
This hair is from
his daughter's head.
I promised him
that if he went
to Earl Haraldson
I would find a way to kill her.
I still don't see Knut.
Well, that's because
he isn't here.
He hasn't sent word either.
That troubles me.
We live in a sea of troubles.
But look, some are ended.
Here, this is yours.
And this is mine.
Master.
May the gods bless us
with powerful winds
and calm seas.
Come here, slave.
Leif, cover the ravens.
Feel that wind;
That breeze is up.
Ready the oars!
Come.
Well?
They have set sail.
Good.
They'll never be
heard from again.
But...
But what?
What if Ragnar is right?
There are no lands to the west!
Get out.
It's noon.
Let's look at the board.
Get the bucket.
Not too far South.
Nor too far north.
The board works.
How do we know?
The great sea is
held in place by Jormungand,
the serpent,
whose giant body encircles it
and who keeps his tail
in his mouth
to complete the circle
and stop the waves
breaking loose.
But one day, the God Thor,
son of earth,
was fishing in the sea
for the serpent,
using a bull's head for bait.
Jormungand reared up
and the waves pummeled
the shore
as he twisted and writhed
in a fury.
They were well matched,
serpent and God,
in that furious fight.
The seas boiled around them,
but then the hook
became dislodged,
and the serpent slithered free
and sank again, so quickly,
beneath the waves.
And soon, the sea was calm
once more,
as if nothing had disturbed it.
Thor.
Storm's coming.
Should we let down the sail?
Floki, should we let down
the sail?
Yes, we have to take
the sail down,
and then we must row.
If we are not moving forward,
then we will be soaked
by the waves and sink.
Ready?
Keep her straight!
You heard him!
Tent!
Shove the oars!
Row!
Are you afraid?
Floki yes, Ragnar
Lothbrok, I am afraid.
But not for me.
I am afraid for my boat.
Thor is striking his anvil.
He is angry with us.
He wants to sink us.
It's true!
Thor is beating his hammer.
The lightning is the sparks
from his anvil.
But he's not angry with us.
I understand now.
Why should he be angry with us?
Why should he want to sink
our boat?
Don't you understand?
He is celebrating.
He is full of good news.
He wants to show everybody
that he can't sink this boat.
He loves this boat!
Sit down, you idiot!
It's my boat,
and the gods love my boat.
Why should I...
Not be happy?!
Floki, sit down.
Remember, you can't swim!
Father Cuthbert!
What is it, brother Athelstan?
We can all see the signs.
Signs? What signs?
Of what do you speak?
You know as well as we
that judgment day is at hand.
Jeremiah says so!
"And on that day,
the sun shall be darkened,"
and the moon shall
not give her light,
"and the stars of heaven
shall fall."
In the name of God,
that is enough.
But it's true!
"And I stood upon
the sand of the sea,"
and saw a beast rise up
out of the sea,
"having seven heads
and ten horns."
I will hear no more!
You will return
to your dormitory
and pray to God for forgiveness
and humility...
And when the storm has passed
all shall be well.
You will do as I order.
Yes, father.
Father!
Good day to you, blacksmith.
My lord, how
can I be of use to you?
You make anchors, don't you?
Yes, lord.
Have you made any recently?
No, not recently,
lord Haraldson.
You didn't forge an anchor
for a man called
Ragnar Lothbrok?
I would have remembered.
Don't hurt my daughter.
Why would I hurt your daughter?
His lordship just wants
to know the truth.
Did you forge the anchor
for Ragnar Lothbrok's ship?
Yes, I forged it.
Let go of her.
Put down your hammer.
I promise you no harm
will come to your daughter.
Look in the flames.
The sages say that
we can see our future
in the flames.
No!
Please, no!
What do you see?
I see my own death.
No! No!
Noooooooo!
There is no west!
We are not sailing towards
any new country
but just into an empty ocean...
Utterly and completely lost.
Kauko, leif...
We have been persuaded
by madmen and fools.
The God loki
is behind this voyage.
That scoundrel, that sly one.
Trouble and suffering are meat
and drink to him.
Shut up, man!
No!
No.
If anyone is mad, it is you.
I'm not the one who convinced
all these good men
to sacrifice their lives
for a dream,
an illusion.
It wasn't me who joined forces
with the sly one
to get us to sail west,
into nothing, into nowhere.
He's mad!
Don't tempt the gods!
Oh, and here we are, lost,
certain to die.
For what?
Sit down and shut up.
You sound like the sly one.
Perhaps you are
the God of mischief
who sends men mad,
and sends them to their deaths.
Sit down!
I curse the day I ever agreed
to come with you,
Ragnar Lothbrok.
For this ship is cursed,
and we are...
Release the ravens.
If the birds do not return,
there is land.
But if they do...
They've come back.
There's no land.
Seabirds!
Seagulls!
Listen!
Woo!
- It works! Yeah!
- We made it!
Row! We made it!
Row!
Ragnar, you did it!
Tie the sail!
Oars! Drop the oars!
What is it?
Why was the warning bell rung?
They've come. They are here.
Who is here?
Hell - and all its devils!
Lock the doors and stay inside,
all of you! Hurry.
They know we're here.
No one throw their lives away
unnecessarily,
even to impress the gods.
Stay close.
There are here!
Come, brother!
Ahh! Quick!
Arne, get to work.
Father Cuthbert
don't be afraid.
Trust in God,
and let us pray.
In nomine patris
et fili et spiritus sancti.
Pater noster qui es in caelis.
Pater noster qui-agggghhhhhh!
This is the end!
The son of man cometh!
Aghhhhh!
Leif.
Ungh!
Ugh!
Ungh! Ungh!
I don't understand.
Why do they leave such
treasures unprotected?
Is there some spell,
some magic which protects them?
It appears not.
Perhaps they think
their God protects them.
If this is their God,
then he's dead.
He is nailed to a cross.
He cannot protect anyone.
He is not alive, like Odin,
Thor or Frey.
What use is he then?
Don't kill me.
You speak our language.
How do you speak our language?
I've travelled.
We are told to travel,
to take the word of God.
Please, don't kill me.
What is that
you have in your hand?
A book...
The gospels of st John,
I... I wanted to save it.
Of all the treasures
I see in this place,
you chose to save this?
Yes.
Hmm. Why?
Why?
Because without the word of God
there is only darkness.
This is a strange place indeed.
We have been everywhere
and we have found no women.
Just these strange men.
I believe they are
the priests of their God.
Take what you will.
This is what we came for.
Why have you not killed
this one?
He is worth more alive...
to sell as a slave.
I would kill him.
We have no room left
on the boat.
I forbid it.
How can you forbid
it, little brother?
We are all equals,
and I say he dies.
Does it really mean
that much to you, brother?
This is what we care
for your God.
So much gold!
Look!
Keep them moving!
Ugh!
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com